

Milena Vásquez-Amézquita

Faculty of Psychology, Universidad El Bosque

[(+57) 601-6489000 Ext. 1605 | ■mvasquezam@unbosque.edu.co | 100000-0001-7317-8430 | ■XgNEpfgAAAA | Milena-Vasquez-Amezquita | 💣 grupo-codec.netlify.app/author/milena-vasquez-amezquita/

I am a researcher primarily interested in the neurocognitive bases of human affect and sexuality.

About me_

Psychologist, Master in Basic and Applied Neurosciences and PhD in Neurosciences. Active associate researcher within the group CODEC: Cognitive and Behavioural Sciences (classification A1 in MinCiencias). Associate Professor at the Laboratory of Experimental Psychology of the Faculty of Psychology at Universidad El Bosque. Postdoctoral stay at Universidad de la Costa with funding from MinCiencias. I have been director and co-director of successful research projects from an experimental methodology in cognitive-affective neuroscience with internal and external funding, and I currently directing the research hotbed **SexCog**: sexuality and affectivity from a neurocognitive perspective. I have 13 years of professional and university teaching experience, applied to the development and implementation of undergraduate and postgraduate higher education programmes related to the neurobiological and cognitive bases of human behaviour, and I have supervised undergraduate, masters and doctoral degree projects.



Skills

Programming R (Basic, data analysis and graph generation)

Quantitative Research Observational-correlational studies, Simple and Mixed general linear models

Recording techniques Eye tracking (mainly), other basic HRV, EEG

Software RStudio, Tobii Pro Lab, Qualtrics, Psychomorph, WebmorphR, Mendeley and Zotero

Languages English/Spanish (native)

Education

Universidad de Valencia

Valencia, España PhD - Neurosciences

Valencia, España

2018

Universidad de Valencia

MASTER'S DEGREE IN BASIC AND APPLIED NEUROSCIENCES

Universidad Cátolica de Colombia

Bogotá, Colombia Psychology 2007

Research Experience

Universidad El Bosque

Bogotá, Colombia ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR Jan. 2020 - Present

Universidad de la Costa Barranquilla, Colombia

VISITING PROFESSOR Dec.2023 - Present

Universidad Internacional de Valencia Valencia, España

COLLABORATING PROFESSOR Oct.2023 - Present

Professional Experience

For a full list, and a description of responsibilities, please check my academic CV.

ONG RedPapaz

EXTERNAL SCIENTIFIC CONSULTANT

Protect Children

INTERNATIONAL SCIENTIFIC CONSULTANT

Bogotá, Colombia Sep. - Oct. 2022 Helsink, Finlandia

Jul. - Aug. 2021

Accomplishments

For information on grants, scholarships, awards and prizes, please check my academic CV.

Selected Publications

9 *h*-index 16

8 i10-index

16 Publications

442 Citations

For a full list, please check the publications section on my academic CV.

q-index

- **Vásquez-Amézquita, M.**, Leongoméz, J. D., Salvador, A., & Seto, M. C. (2023). What can the eyes tell us about atypical sexual preferences as a function of sex and age? Linking eye movements with child-related chronophilias. *Forensic Sciences Research*, 8(1)1–11. https://doi.org/10.1093/fsr/owad009
- **Vásquez-Amézquita, M.**, Salvador, A., & Leongómez, J. D. (2021). Existen diferencias en la ratio 2D:4D entre delincuentes sexuales y no sexuales, y hombres no delincuentes? Un estudio en una muestra colombiana. Interdisciplinaria. *Revista de Psicología y Ciencias Afines*, 39(1). https://doi.org/10.16888/interd.20 22.39.1.8
- Jones, B. C., DeBruine, L. M., Flake, J. K., Liuzza, M. T., Antfolk, J., Arinze, N. C., Ndukaihe, I. L. G., Bloxsom, N. G., Lewis, S. C., Foroni, F., Willis, M. L., Cubillas, C. P., Vadillo, M. A., Turiegano, E., Gilead, M., Simchon, A., Saribay, S. A., Owsley, N. C., Jang, C. ..., Vásquez-Amézquita, M., ..., Coles, N. A. (2021). To which world regions does the valence–dominance model of social perception apply? *Nature Human Behaviour*, *5*(1) 159-169. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-01007-2
- **Vásquez-Amézquita, M.**, Leongómez, J. D., Seto, M. C., Bonilla, F. M., Rodríguez-Padilla, A., & Salvador, A. (2018). No relation between digit ratio (2D:4D) and visual attention patterns to sexually preferred and non-preferred stimuli. *Personality and Individual Differences*, 120, 151–158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2017.08.022
- **Vásquez-Amézquita, M.**, Leongómez, J. D., Seto, M. C., Bonilla, M., Rodríguez-Padilla, A., & Salvador, A. (2019). Visual Attention Patterns Differ in Gynephilic and Androphilic Men and Women Depending on Age and Gender of Targets. *The Journal of Sex Research*, *56*(1), 85–101. https://doi.org/10.1080/00224499.2017.13 72353
- **Vásquez-Amézquita, M.**, Leongómez, J. D., Seto, M. C., & Salvador, A. (2019). Differences in Visual Attention Patterns to Sexually Mature and Immature Stimuli Between Heterosexual Sexual Offenders, Nonsexual Offenders, and Nonoffending Men. *The Journal of Sex Research*, *56* (2), 213–228. https://doi.org/10.1080/0022 4499.2018.1511965

Postgraduate Supervision

For a full list, including undergraduate supervision, please check my academic CV.

Sara Silva Gómez

MSc in Neuropsychology

Yenny Johanna Baron Londoño

MSc in Psychology

Universidad Internacional de Valencia, España 2022-2023 Universidad El Bosque, Colombia

2019 - 2020